picsquare.com 2011-12-31

# Picsquare - Privacy Policy

#### At Picsquare we are committed to provide a fun, easy, and safe environment for you to upload, view, share and print your photos and enjoy sending photo gifts. Protecting your privacy is extremely important to Picsquare and is one of our top objectives when designing the website and its infrastructure. We recognize and respect the importance of maintaining the privacy of our customers and look forward to maintaining the trust in our business relationship. We have created this privacy policy to disclose and explain you why we gather customer and member information, what information we collect, how we collect it, what we use the information for and how you can instruct us to limit the use of that information. We have designed our procedures and processes for handling your data with the same high quality care and security that we would expect our own personal data to be handled.

#### Picsquare knows that you care how information about you is used and shared, and we appreciate your trust that we will do so carefully and sensibly. At Picsquare, we let you retain as much control as possible over your personal information. However, you may not visit and use our site at anytime without telling us who you are or revealing the required information about yourself. This notice describes our privacy policy. By visiting Picsquare?s site, you are accepting the practices described in this Privacy Policy.

### What Information do we gather?

#### We collect and store only a very limited amount of data and personal information necessary to process your account and to operate and improve Picsquare services. You can be assured that your information is protected. Your individual, and personal data will not be distributed.

#### We will retain information you may have requested us to remove if, in our discretion, retention of the information is necessary to resolve disputes, troubleshoot problems, or to enforce the Terms of Services agreement. Furthermore, your information is never completely removed from our databases due to technical and legal constraints. For example, we will not remove your information from our back-up storage systems.

#### The personal information about you, that Picsquare may possibly collect are:

### **Email**

#### We collect and store your e-mail address when you provide it to us at the time of registration. The email address is used as a unique username so that we may easily identify you in our records and you may be uniquely identified online by other users.

### **Name**

#### We collect and store your e-mail address when you provide it to us at the time of registration. The email address is used as a unique username so that we may easily identify you in our records and you may be uniquely identified online by other users.

### **Postal Address**

#### We collect and store the shipping/postal address (town, city, state, country and postal code) at the time of ordering photos/gifts from Picsquare. The addresses are used to ship the orders at the correct location and also store them in the users address book for future convenience.

### **Phone Number**

#### We collect the phone number at the time of ordering photos/gifts and will only use it in the rare emergency that we need to contact you by phone, such as a billing question when processing your order, or if we suspect that someone may be using your account fraudulently. These calls will not be made to sell you anything. We may collect your mobile phone number and to enable services for your mobile device.

### **Password**

#### We collect and store your password so that you may access your account securely at the time of registration.

### **Photos**

#### We collect the photos, when the subscriber uploads them in their account at their discretion, to store, view, share, print and make gifts from them. Your photos are as private as you make them. No one should be able to view your photos unless they have your e-mail address (username) and password.

### **Friends' E-mail Addresses**

#### We collect your friend's email addresses and names when you use our Tell a Friend feature or add their details in the address book. Names and e-mail addresses are stored for the purpose of making it easy for you to use them again in the future.

### **Messages**

#### We collect and store your testimonial message(s) so that other visitors may view your messages. We also collect and store data about your use of the customer testimonial, including how many messages you have posted, when those messages were posted, and other data similar to online forum discussion systems.

### **Feedback**

#### We collect your feedback, suggestions, and information that you give to us, including information about your preferences.

### **Who collects the information?**

#### We will collect personally identifiable information about you only as part of a voluntary registration process, on-line survey, or contest. Visitors of Picsquare who do not have Picsquare accounts are not required to log into the website or provide any personal information to view pictures. We only collect personal information from users who are not Picsquare subscribers when they sign up for a newsletter or otherwise wish to communicate with others on the website. Please note that we have no control over any information that is disclosed publicly. You should exercise caution when disclosing your personal information at places in the website which are accessible to anyone.

### **How we use the information we collect about you?**

#### The information we collect about you is used for the following purposes:

#### Improve and enhance our content and product offerings, marketing and promotional efforts.

#### Respond to your inquiries, resolve disputes, troubleshoot problems, and enforce our Terms of Services agreement.

#### Analyze the site usage and customize our website's content, layout, and services.

#### Provide the services you've requested, including services that display customized content and advertising.

#### Auditing, research and analysis to operate and improve Picsquare technologies and services.

#### Email - We will only use your e-mail address for the following reasons:

  * Signing up for subscriptions;
  * Using the Tell a Friend, Testimonial feature;
  * Requesting the periodic e-mail newsletter;
  * Participating in promotions and contests;
  * Sending messages directly to Picsquare, such as through the Contact Us page;

#### If you wish discontinue receiving the newsletter, you can send a request through the Contact Us page, or follow the instructions in the newsletter or in the Help section of Picsquare.

### **Name**

#### We collect and store your name so that we may identify you properly and respectfully.

### **Postal Address**

#### The addresses are used to ship the orders (physical products) at the correct location and also store them in the users address book for future convenience. We will not send you anything unexpectedly and without your consent.

### **Phone Number**

#### The phone number will be used only in case of emergency, when we need to contact you by phone, e.g. a billing question when processing your order for confirmation, or if we suspect that someone may be using your account fraudulently. These calls will not be made to sell you anything.

### **Password**

#### We recommend you to keep your password confidential and secure at all times. As per Picsquare Terms of Service agreement, you acknowledge and agree that you are entirely responsible for maintaining the confidentiality of your password and account. Furthermore, you acknowledge and agree that you are entirely responsible for any and all activities that occur under your account.

#### We strongly recommend you to regularly change your password. There will be no communication by Picsquare over the phone confirming/asking for your password. Please do not give any information, if you are ever contacted by someone claiming to be an employee of Picsquare, asking for your personal billing information or password. Report the incident to us with as much detail as possible, and we will investigate.

### **Photos**

#### Your photos are as private as you make them. No one should be able to view your photos unless they have your e-mail address (username) and password. These photographs are stored, used to share, order prints and photo gifts by the subscriber. All of your photos are password protected and are not visible to others unless you explicitly share them. You can invite visitors to see your photos by following the instructions at the website. We will send an email to your list of invitees containing the URL to your photos. Please note that your invitees can then forward the email containing the URL to other parties, if they choose.

#### Friends' E-mail Addresses - Names, e-mail addresses and shipping address of friends are stored for the purpose of making it easy for you to use them again in the future. We will not use the addresses you provide for any other purposes.

### **Messages**

#### We collect and store your testimonial message so that other visitors may view your messages. We also collect and store data about your use of the customer testimonial, including how many messages you have posted, when those messages were posted, and other data similar to other online forum discussion systems.

### **Feedback**

#### We collect your feedback, suggestions, and information that you give to us, including information about your preferences.

### **Search Engines**

#### Some search engines and websites not affiliated with Picsquare, may cache, archive, or otherwise store Picsquare pages, including your testimonial messages. Picsquare does not have control of the information or pages on those websites.

### **Third-party Suppliers**

#### We may share your personal information with carefully selected third-party suppliers who provide services to deliver certain features of Picsquare. For example, to fulfill your order for a physical product, such as prints, we may disclose certain portions of your personal information to our suppliers to properly fulfill your order and to deliver excellent services and products to you. Those portions of your personal information may include your name, shipping address, your e-mail address, and the products you ordered. Our suppliers will only be permitted to use your personal information to fulfill your order; other uses of your personal information are prohibited. We will endeavor to ensure that our suppliers' privacy policies and data management systems are at a similar high level of security and integrity as Picsquare so that your data is protected and safe.

### **Credit Card Information**

#### We do not store any credit card information of the subscriber. When a subscriber does any transaction with , he/she is redirected to the Third-party website where he is required to fill in his credit card details. After the transaction is completed with the third-party website, he will get a confirmation page showing the status of the transaction. Picsquare does not have any control of the information on those websites and does not take any responsibility for the misuse of the credit card information provided by the subscriber to the third party.

### **Automatic Information**

#### We receive and store certain types of information whenever you interact with us. For example, like many web sites, we use "cookies," and we obtain certain types of information when your Web browser accesses Picsquare?s Site.

### **About Cookies**

#### Cookies are alphanumeric identifiers that we transfer to your computer's hard drive through your Web browser to enable our systems to recognize your browser and to provide certain features.

#### The "help" portion of the toolbar on most browsers will tell you how to prevent your browser from accepting new cookies, how to have the browser notify you when you receive a new cookie, or how to disable cookies altogether. However, cookies allow you to take full advantage of some of the Site?s best and updated features, and we recommend that you leave them turned on.

### **With whom is your information shared?**

#### We may share your personal information with carefully selected third-party suppliers who provide services to deliver certain features of Picsquare. For example, to fulfill your order for a physical product, such as prints, we may disclose certain portions of your personal information to our suppliers to properly fulfill your order and to deliver excellent services and products to you. Those portions of your personal information may include your name, shipping address, your e-mail address, and the products you ordered. Our suppliers will only be permitted to use your personal information to fulfill your order; other uses of your personal information are prohibited. We will endeavor to ensure that our suppliers' privacy policies and data management systems are at a similar high level of security and integrity as Picsquare so that your data is protected and safe.

### **How do we ensure your security?**

### **Password-Protection**

#### When you create your Picsquare account, you choose a private password for yourself. Be sure to keep your password confidential, safe, and secure. If someone knows your password, they have access to your account and your personal information, and you are responsible for their activities. If you feel that your password is no longer private and confidential, be sure to change it, or send a message to Picsquare requesting your password be changed. If you feel that an unauthorized person has accessed your account, contact Picsquare immediately. To ensure that you have properly logged out of your account, be sure to close your browser, especially on public computers, such as those found in libraries, schools and cyber-cafes.

### **Data Security**

#### Picsquare uses latest, up-to-date electronic and physical security measures to protect the loss, misuse, and alteration of the data under our control. Picsquare has implemented Secure 128-bit Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) data encryption to protect your personal information. Your personal and confidential information resides in a database on a server that is not directly accessible from the Internet. Our servers are heavily guarded, located behind multiple hardware and software firewalls. Backups of your data are conducted daily. Our servers are running a version of the Linux operating system that is industry-renowned for its stability and security. Access to your personal information is password protected and limited to staff members who are authorized to use your personal information for business and administrative purposes. Picsquare is always investigating new techniques to ensure strong data protection.

### **Links to Third-party Websites**

#### Picsquare, its subscribers, and visitors, may provide links to third-party websites, which may have privacy policies different from the privacy policy on Picsquare. We are not responsible for, nor have any control over, the privacy policies of those third-party websites, and encourage you to read the privacy policies of each and every website you visit. When you click on links to other websites, those websites may attach a cookie to your hard drive and may collect information about you. Picsquare makes no claims or representations about what information those websites do or do not collect about you. Please review any Terms of Services Agreements and Privacy Policies of those other websites to learn about their data collection and data use practices.

### **Personal Information and Data**

#### As per our Terms and Services Agreement, you are solely responsible for, and Picsquare is not liable for, the personal information and other materials that you post, upload, submit, and otherwise make available on the website, including areas of the website that are available to the public. We have no control over and cannot protect personal information that you disclose in public areas of Picsquare. If you disclose your personal information in public areas, it may be collected and used by third parties, without our or your knowledge. You should also understand that by displaying your photographs on Picsquare and the Internet, for the intention of showing those photographs to your friends, family, acquaintences, clients, business partners, and others, that you directly intended to see the photographs, you are relinquishing certain traditional privacy rights, wherein anyone with access to the Internet has the potential ability to view your photographs. If you do not wish to relinquish these traditional privacy rights, do not share your photographs.

### **Advertising**

#### Picsquare will not run third-party advertisements on subscribers' photo pages. The reason is that some advertising banners may collect your data, which we will not allow. It will not run banner ads, pop ups, pop unders, or any other kind of annoying advertisement method anywhere on the site. Picsquare may offer sponsorships, contests, promotions, and advertisements in the periodic newsletter and on areas of the website that are available to visitors for free. Picsquare will not rent, share, sell, or otherwise disclose your personal data to any third party for marketing purposes. Picsquare will not send you unsolicited e-mail communications for marketing purposes. When you participate in a promotion, contest, or survey, we may ask you for personal information, including information about your photography equipment and use. Participation in any survey or contest is completely voluntary and you therefore have a choice whether or not to disclose this information

### **Law Enforcement**

#### Picsquare will not rent, share, sell, or otherwise disclose your personal data to any third party, except for law enforcement purposes, as stated in the Picsquare Terms of Services agreement.

#### Picsquare may disclose information about its users to law enforcement officers or others, in the good faith belief that such disclosure is reasonably necessary to:

* Respond to subpoenas, court orders, judicial proceedings, or other legal processes;
* Enforce our Terms of Services agreement;
* Respond to claims that any photo, text, or other material violates the rights of third-parties;
* Or protect the rights, property, or personal safety of Picsquare, its users, or the general public;

#### No one from Picsquare will ever call you and ask for your password. If you are ever contacted by someone claiming to be an employee of Picsquare, and the person asks you for your personal billing information or password, do not give them any information; instead, report the incident to us with as much detail as possible, and we will investigate.

### **How can you correct inaccuracies in the information?**

#### You can help Picsquare maintain the accuracy of your personal information by:

* Notifying us when you change your name, address, phone number, e-mail address, or your newsletter preferences;
* Update your information from the My Account page;
* Contacting us at any time via our Contact Us page;

#### If you no longer wish to receive our newsletter, you may opt-out by following the instructions in the newsletter or by sending us your request via our Contact Us page.

### **How do we handle Changes to this Policy?**

### **Notification**

#### As the Picsquare website continues to develop, we will add new features, and we may change the type of information we collect or the method by which the information is collected. We will update this privacy policy to reflect any changes, and we will provide you notice of significant changes to the privacy policy by posting notice at www.picsquare.com and through other methods as appropriate.

### **Policy Differences**

#### If we update our privacy policy, any information you have provided us before the policy change will be used in accordance with the privacy policy in effect when your information was collected. If we are going to use your personal information in a manner different from that stated at the time of collection, we will notify you via e-mail. You will have a choice as to whether or not we can use your information in this different manner. If you no longer have an active or valid account, then you will not be contacted, and your personal information not be used. If we make any material changes in our privacy policy that do not affect your personal information already stored in our database, we will post notification on our website notifying you of the change. In some cases when we post a notice, we will also e-mail users who have opted to receive communications notifying them of the changes in our privacy practices.
